Notice Period: 3 Months

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electronics/Telecommunication]

Akshatha Shetty (1) Featured

IBM Integration bus and IBM mg developer.



Current Designation: Application Development Analyst Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

Current Company: Accenture
Current Location: Mumbai

Pref. Location: Mumbai,Bengaluru / Bangalore,Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Ibm Integration Bus, ESQL, Message Broker, MQ, Mule Esb, Java

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 17-Jan-21 Last Modified: 17-Jan-21

Summary

A Software Professional with more than 4.5 years of development expertise in IBM Integration Bus, IBM MQ, Oracle database and Java.

Experience in designing & developing message flows using different nodes.

Strong programming knowledge of ESQL and Java.

Work Experience

Accenture as Application Development Analyst Apr 2019 to Till Date

Currently working as middleware developer in Accenture and the project under which I am working is LOBLAW which is Canada's Largest Retail Company.

Tech Mahindra as Software Engineer -IT Aug 2016 to Mar 2019

Technical Environment: IBM Integration BUS.

Duration: Aug 2016 - Till date.

Project Description

Implementation of Customer Relationship Management (CRM) solution at SBI. IBM Integration Bus was used to integrate CRM with other core systems of the bank. IIB was used for transformation of data, orchestrations of services available from other bank systems.

Roles and Responsibilities:

Interacted with the client and the front-end team for understanding the requirements.

Designed and developed message flows.

Wrote ESQL codes for performing transformations and orchestrations and aggregation of web services and database operations.

Wrote java codes to standardize the various encryption methodologies used by different systems of the bank to provide a

single banking standard encryption for the CRM

Deployed BAR files in all environments (Non-Prod and Prod).

Documentation of services built.

Configured integration node and integration server to change the default ports, connect to database by creating new data source, established HTTPS connectivity by setting up the keystore.

Interacted with the network team regarding traffic flow to IIB servers.

Rectified bugs by proper troubleshooting.

Achievements:

Awarded with 'Pat on Back' and 'spot' award for excellent individual performance.

Team was awarded with 'Best Team Award' for best overall performance amongst all other teams in the entire project.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Mangalore Institute of Technology & Engineering, Karnataka in 2016

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
JAVA	7	2018	4 Year(s) 4 Month(s)	
Oracle	12c	2018	4 Year(s) 4 Month(s)	
SQL	12	2018	4 Year(s) 4 Month(s)	
IBM MQ	9	2018	4 Year(s) 4 Month(s)	
IIB 10, MQ 9	10	2018	4 Year(s) 5 Month(s)	
Unix shell scripting				
Tortoise SVN				
Soap UI, PostMan				
RFHUtil, SQL Developer				

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: LOBLAW Companies Ltd

Client: Loblaw

Nature of Employment: Full Time
Project Location: Navi Mumbai
Role: Programmer

Duration: Apr 2019 - Till Date
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite
Team Size: 8

Skill Used: Ibm Integration Bus, ESQL, WMB, Unix Shell Scripting, Core Java

Role Description: Designed and developed message flows to transform the data and orchestration of services available in

Loblaw system

Project Details: Loblaw Companies Limited is the largest Canadian food retailer, encompassing corporate and franchise supermarkets.

Duration: Feb 2017 - Mar 2019

Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Title: SBI CRM Impact Client: State Bank Of India Nature of Employment: Full Time Project Location: Mumbai

Role: Programmer Team Size: 5

Skill Used: Ibm Integration Bus, ESQL, WMB, Message Broker, MQ

Role Description: Result oriented and Software professional with 2 years of experience in IBM Integration Bus, IBM MQ,

Oracle Database and JAVA in Banking and Financial domain.

Project Details: Implementation of Customer Relationship Management (CRM) solution at SBI.

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Category: General

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time